Hello everyone and
welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco. My name
is Catherine and today we have
another holiday
lesson for you guys.
It's an intermediate-level lesson
but it's not about Christmas
and it's not about New Year's.
So what's this holiday model?
It's like after Christmas
but before New Year's.
Okay so let's look at this holiday
in today's vocabulary preview.
Very vocabulary preview.
Alright so as you notice
in the title this is
called Boxing Day.
So like fighting boxing.
Kind of like boxes right?
It's more related to to
boxes. Exactly so this is a
holiday that we don't
actually celebrate in America.
It's celebrated in what
are called common
wealth countries. That
means countries that used
to be a part of Great
Britain or that are a part
of Great Britain. So England,
Scotland, Canada, Australia.
And this is a day where well it's considered
a holiday because it's a bank holiday.
That means all the banks close.
No one's at work. It's the day
after Christmas so it's December
26th and it's traditionally
a day when you give
money or gifts to the poor.
Okay and so this is more
or less what we're going
to be talking about but
more modern right before
it was like that but now
it's kind of become this
shopping thing right?
It has. It's a day when
everyone goes to the sales
after Christmas to return
things or to buy new things.
So we're going to
hear about this right
away in today's dialogue
and when we come back
we'll be talking about some of the
phrases and words that you've heard.
What do you think of this one?
Eh, so so. And this one? Too flashy?
Nah not too flashy. Oh
and this sweater from my
aunt, isn't it hideous?
Yes. Are you even listening?
I'm trying to have a conversation with you.
And I'm trying to watch the game but you're
yapping on about
your new clothes.
Well I have to decide
which gifts to keep and which
to exchange for better
ones when I go to the
boxing day sales this
afternoon. Well could you
do me the favor of making
this quick? It's the third
quarter you've been
blabbering on since the first.
Oh you're precious game. You watch the
same game every year and each year you'll
beloved hometown team
loses by at least three goals.
Oh no you didn't.
You didn't just insult
the Salisbury Seals did
you? Why don't you just
go return all those stupid
clothes and not come
back until the sales are
over. I might just enjoy
your stupid game and Merry
Christmas. Merry Christmas.
All right great so we're
back and interesting
the couple fighting
right after Christmas.
Well I think it's very
common to hear fights
around the holidays.
People are very stressed out
and tired of dealing
with family and presence
and all the stress right.
In fact but we'll talk
about that a little bit
later on right now why
don't we take a look at
four key words in language
takeaway. Language
takeaway. Okay these first
two words are words
that the wife uses in talking
about some of these clothes
that she got as presents.
So she says well she
asks her husband is this
two flashy flashy flashy
all right so you know
flash like the camera
flash right this big light
now flashy when you're
talking about clothes
or an object is it it's
too noticeable right.
It's too noticeable too
bright too loud so for example
a black shirt is not
flashy but an orange shirt
with buttons and bells
and black rhinestones
diamonds that's flashy
okay flashy can also
mean something that is it's
supposed to look expensive.
Okay so that
sweater was a little bit
flashy according to her and but also she
talked about another sweater being hideous.
So hideous is an ugly
word and it means ugly ugly.
Okay so I could say this
sweater is hideous that means
it's not only ugly
it's really ugly.
Okay it's more than ugly
all right a hideous sweater
and moving on the guy now was a little
bit irritated and stressed out and he said
you keep yapping on
about your new clothes so
what is this yapping on?
Well yap is a sound like
yap yap yap yap yap yap
yap so yapping to yap on
about means to continue
to talk and talk and talk
about something okay
because he's watching the
football game on TV and
she's talking and talking
and talking and he's
annoyed so this is rude you
say stop yapping about
this sorry stop yapping
on about your game
all right it's very rude it
means just stop talking
I'm annoyed and well then
he mentioned another phrase that it's pretty
much the same thing right blabbering on
to blabber to blabber on
about means to talk about
something but to not
really make sense okay so
it's just worthless talk
so you're just talking
to talk you're not
really saying anything
interesting exactly and
so sometimes we make fun
of people who blabber
on about things because
they're not important
to us or they sound stupid
all right okay so four key
words there blabbering
on yapping on why don't
we listen to them again
in the dialogue what
do you think of this one
eh so so and this one
too flashy no not too
flashy oh and this sweater
from my aunt isn't it
hideous I guess are you
even listening I'm trying
to have a conversation
with you and I'm trying to
watch the game but you're
yapping on about your
new clothes well I have
to decide which gifts
to keep in which to
exchange for better ones
when I go to the boxing
day sales this afternoon
well could you do me
the favor of making this
quick it's the third
quarter and you've been
blabbering on since
the first oh your precious
game you watch the same
game every year and each
year your beloved hometown
team loses by at least
three goals oh no you
didn't you didn't just
insult the cells where
he seals did you well why
don't you just just go
return all those stupid
clothes and not come
back until the sales are
over I might just enjoy
your stupid game and merry
Christmas merry Christmas
all right we're back
so now we have a couple
of different phrases that
we want to look at on
fluency builder fluency
builder okay so this
first phrase is very closely
related to the the days
after Christmas especially
here on boxing day
we've got someone who's
talking about going
to the stores to the sales
to exchange her gifts
for better gifts okay
to exchange something
for something better this
is a very common
construction it's an important
phrase when talking about
shopping so when we look
at this construction you
would say to exchange
this sweater for a better
one or for a larger one
exactly so you can change
the adjective the word
that's describing it so
you can say to exchange
these shoes for bigger
ones I could also joke and
I could say I'm gonna
exchange my boyfriend for a
better one right he's
being rude to me okay so to
exchange something
for something else exactly
all right and then we saw
another phrase that the
husband replied to when
she offended him with
his football team he said
oh no you didn't didn't
what I know didn't what
no you didn't what all
right so this like he said
doesn't make sense alone
but some cultural context
might help in English
we often say say this
phrase to mean oh no you
didn't just say that
you didn't just insult my
team he's saying I can't
believe you just said that
he's upset because
what she said was rude or
mean okay okay so I
could say you know Marco I
think Ecuador sucks oh
oh no you didn't I did just
say I don't think so
actually but it's usually a
response right you have
to wait until somebody
maybe says something
mean or something that
you know really hurts
your feelings or you don't
agree with when you
respond to this but you're
usually very very
offended right exactly it's
always a response to a
comment that has made you
angry or upset okay and
our last phrase is when
they finished talking
and they were fighting
she left and said I
might just just what just
what see again these are
common phrases but they
don't seem to make my
sense alone I might just
so let's listen to this
is a response again this
is a response to the line
before it um why don't
you just just go and
return all of those stupid
clothes and not come
back until much later and
she says I might just I
might just do exactly what
you just said okay she's
threatening him she's
saying I might just go
out and not come back for
10 hours all right I
might just do that okay so
that's a way to say what
you said I might do that
and I'm threatening
you so again it's usually
a response right or
a threat as you said
so I can say Marco why
don't you just leave all
right I might just oh
what am I gonna do in this
studio now all right so
three interesting phrases
there why don't we
listen to all the words and
phrases again in a
dialogue one last time what
do you think of this one
yeah so so and this one
too flashy no not too
flashy oh and this sweater
from my aunt isn't it
hideous yes are you even
listening I'm trying to
have a conversation with
you and I'm trying to
watch the game but you're
yapping on about your
new clothes well I have
to decide which gifts
to keep in which to
exchange for better ones
when I go to the boxing
day sales this afternoon
well could you do
me the favor of making
this quick it's the third
quarter you've been
blabbering on since the first
oh your precious game
you watch the same game
every year and each year
your beloved hometown team
loses by at least three
goals oh no you didn't
you didn't just insult
the cells where he seals
did you well why don't
you just just go return
all those stupid clothes
and not come back
until the salesroom I
might just enjoy your
stupid game and merry
Christmas all right we're
back so boxing day
as you said is usually a
common well thing in
the United States you don't
really have it right we
do not my family I don't
know why but my family
sometimes celebrates
that we have friends who
come over and we have
a nice boxing day meal
but okay I've been told
that the tradition in
commonwealth countries is
to watch sporting events
local sporting events
and to go shopping
for all these boggins and
bargains and exchange
all those ugly hideous
annoying or or bad gifts
that you received at Christmas
right so it's usually
like the after Christmas
sales exactly so if you
have any special boxing
day traditions I'd be
very curious to hear them
again not a holiday
related to the sport boxing
it's well the same way
and it looks the same but
they're very different
no so if you have any
stories or questions about
the things that we talked
about today please do let us
know on our website english pod.
com all right we'll see you guys
there and until next time bye everyone bye